<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss>
  <channel>
    <title>The Economist: Europe</title>
    <description>Europe</description>
    <link>http://www.economist.com</link>
    <image>
      <link>http://www.economist.com</link>
      <width>125</width>
      <title>Economist.com</title>
      <url>//media.economist.com/sites/all/themes/econfinal/images/the-economist-logo.gif</url>
      <height>34</height>
    </image>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <webMaster>webmaster@economist.com</webMaster>
    <managingEditor>rondiorio@economist.com</managingEditor>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <docs>http://www.economist.com/rss/</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Cyprus and the euro: Aphrodite’s indebted island</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN JUNE 2012 the Cypriot government asked for a bail-out after the two largest banks, stacked with Greek bonds, fell victim to the 2011 write-down of Greek debt. Seven months on, time is running out. The finance minister, Vassos Shiarly, says he has to find €1 billion a month to refinance loans and for other spending. Yet the bail-out could be blocked—or approved only with conditions that spark renewed alarm among investors.This week Jörg Asmussen, a European Central Bank board member, said the problems of Cyprus could be “systemic for the rest of the euro area”. Charles Dallara, head of the Washington-based Institute of International Finance, warned of “underestimating the potential contagion impact” coming from the island.The government says it needs €7.5 billion ($10 billion). But its banks also need more capital. A committee including Greek-Cypriot officials and the troika of the European Commission, the ECB and the IMF asked Pimco, a big American bond investor, to advise how much, and the provisional answer was €10.3 billion. But in Germany, especially, any idea of using taxpayers’ money to underwrite deposits in Greek-Cypriot banks meets stiff resistance. Last year Germany’s foreign intelligence service declared that the main beneficiaries would be Russian oligarchs, businessmen and &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;mafios&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;i&lt;/em&gt;....&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570761-could-country-smaller-sicily-reignite-euro-crisis-aphrodites-indebted-island?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570761-could-country-smaller-sicily-reignite-euro-crisis-aphrodites-indebted-island</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe and Britain: The Cameron is coming</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DAVID CAMERON, Britain’s prime minister, annoyed the French last year when he declared that Britain would “roll out the red carpet” for businessmen fleeing France’s 75% tax on the wealthiest. So it was with some glee that Laurent Fabius, the French foreign minister, used the same metaphor to illustrate how France would welcome business fleeing Britain if it ever left the European Union.Such scorn for Mr Cameron’s speech this week, calling for a renegotiation and referendum on Britain’s EU membership, was predictable. But beyond expressions of bafflement and anger round Europe, the response was more nuanced. EU leaders seem ready to consider how to accommodate the British, even if there is a gap between the maximum they can offer and the minimum Mr Cameron can accept.France seems in two minds. Some, such as Michel Rocard, a former Socialist prime minister, have said France should take advantage of a possible “Brixit”. Yet the government values Britain’s presence in the EU, particularly when it comes to defence and foreign policy. Even Mr Fabius speaks warmly of British logistical support for the French operation in Mali.The French president, François Hollande, told his cabinet that he wished “the UK to remain at the heart of the European Union.” His finance minister, Pierre Moscovici, said that “the European spirit is also to respect diversity.” The French are grudgingly...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570706-nuanced-response-david-camerons-european-demands-cameron-coming?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570706-nuanced-response-david-camerons-european-demands-cameron-coming</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlemagne: Europe’s odd couple</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130126_EUD000_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;THE French cockerel and the German eagle have strutted together for so long that few took much notice of this week’s 50th anniversary of the Elysée treaty that sealed their partnership in 1963. The pairing has known memorable times: think of de Gaulle and Adenauer, Giscard d’Estaing and Schmidt, or Mitterrand and Kohl holding hands at the site of Verdun.Now Angela Merkel and François Hollande must tend the near-sacred relationship, a pillar of peace in Europe and of wider co-operation in the European Union. On January 22nd they went through the pomp of celebration in Berlin with joint cabinet meetings, speeches to assembled German and French parliamentarians and an encounter with young people from both sides of the Rhine. Yet for all the words of undying friendship there was something tired and loveless about it all. French opposition leaders talk of relations being marked by “indifference” and even becoming an “empty shell”.Perhaps this is because Mrs Merkel and Mr Hollande come from rival political families. Perhaps they don’t yet know each other well (though in public they use the familiar &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;tu&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;du&lt;/em&gt; forms,...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570698-franco-german-duo-have-lost-their-passion-and-sense-destiny-yet-they-remain?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570698-franco-german-duo-have-lost-their-passion-and-sense-destiny-yet-they-remain</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany’s election year: The vincible chancellor</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130126_EUP004_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;THE incumbent is the leader of the centre-right Christian Democratic Union (CDU), rules in coalition with the liberal Free Democratic Party (FDP), and is more popular than opposition challengers from the Social Democrats (SPD) and the Greens. The only worry is the fate of the FDP. Polls say it may get less than 5% of the votes, the threshold to enter parliament. If the CDU loses its coalition partner, the SPD and Greens combined could be stronger. The CDU’s supporters understand this dilemma and tactically “lend” their votes to the FDP to keep it in parliament. So the FDP surges at the last minute—but entirely at the expense of the CDU. By the narrowest of margins, the centre-left parties then win, and form the new government.This describes the situation in Lower Saxony, a state in northern Germany that held an election on January 20th. A well-liked CDU premier, David McAllister, and his FDP partners lost power to Stephan Weil, the SPD’s candidate, and his Green allies. The margin decided just before midnight, in what a moist-eyed Mr McAllister called a “heart-stopping finale”, was a single seat (69-68). “We are all very sad,” said Angela Merkel, the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570693-local-defeat-albeit-only-hairs-breadth-spells-trouble-angela-merkel-vincible?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570693-local-defeat-albeit-only-hairs-breadth-spells-trouble-angela-merkel-vincible</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dutch and David Cameron: Not wanted here</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130126_EUP003_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;417&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;New kid on the block&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;THE Dutch took David Cameron’s decision to switch venue for his Europe speech from Amsterdam to London as a disenchanted fiancé might treat a break-up: with melancholy but also relief. Some Dutch politicians were excited by the chance to be host to such a defining moment in Britain’s relationship with the European Union. The government also agrees that some EU powers should be repatriated and its budget should be restrained. But there is little sympathy for British Euroscepticism—and some fear of Mr Cameron inveigling the Netherlands into a venture it dislikes.Officials are clear that they oppose more opt-outs for Britain, and want to repatriate powers only on the basis of a deal for all. Members of the ruling coalition have called on Mark Rutte, the prime minister, to distance himself from Mr Cameron, with whom he has a close friendship. The leader of the opposition Christian Democrats said Mr Cameron was “not such a handy ally to have in Europe”. When Mr Cameron demanded treaty changes and an in-out referendum, the government counted itself lucky to be watching from afar.The Netherlands has always tried to...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570709-netherlands-happy-not-be-linked-britains-european-wishes-not-wanted-here?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570709-netherlands-happy-not-be-linked-britains-european-wishes-not-wanted-here</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkish society: Of sex and Islam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130126_EUD001_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;570&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;TURKEY’S prime minister, Recep Tayyip Erdogan, believes that one of the keys to prosperity is a young population. He would love to ban abortion and he nags families to have at least three children. His campaign received an unexpected boost from a respected Islamic theologian, who said on a popular television show that sex was a form of worship. “Sex is a part of worship and, indeed, is the same as &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;namaz &lt;/em&gt;(Muslim prayers),” Ali Riza Demircan told Haberturk TV. A conservative backlash then forced him to clarify that sex and prayers were not of equal virtue.To the delight of TV channels, the Islam and sex debate is growing noisier. A young Islamic counsellor, columnist and TV host, Sibel Uresin, has jumped in, saying that “the path to proper &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;namaz&lt;/em&gt; goes through proper sexual union.” Mrs Uresin (her name means “should reproduce”) also believes that polygamy should be legal because “the Koran says so.” To prove her sincerity she has “offered” a friend to her husband.For Muslims struggling to reconcile their faith with desire there is much online advice. “Is oral sex acceptable?” asks a troubled soul. “To have the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570716-even-imams-discussing-sex-no-longer-taboo-sex-and-islam?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570716-even-imams-discussing-sex-no-longer-taboo-sex-and-islam</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organised crime in Russia: Fathers and sons</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130126_EUP005_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;A godfather’s grave&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;UNIFORMED police were notably absent this week when a few hundred tough-looking, leather-clad men arrived in black Land Cruisers and Mercedes to pay their last respects to a man reputed to be Russia’s mafia boss. Journalists and photographers were told to stay out of the cemetery—for their own sake.The 75-year-old Aslan Usoyan, known as Ded (Grandad) Khasan, was shot dead by a sniper on January 16th as he walked out of a central Moscow restaurant where he often received visitors. He was Russia’s most important “thief-in-law”, a term coined in the Gulag for a criminal bound by a code of honour. “To the Great Patriarch of the thieves’ world, the legendary Grandpa Khasan”, read a banner on one wreath of white roses.He was buried beyond the city limits. The funeral was arranged hurriedly and lacked the pomp usually reserved by the Russian criminal world for its leaders. A plan to bury Mr Usoyan in his native Georgia was aborted when Georgian officials said they did not want him. Clearing the country of mafia bosses has been a main achievement of Mikheil Saakashvili, Georgia’s president. Yet in Moscow Mr Usoyan had...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570721-upsurge-violence-streets-points-rising-instability-fathers-and-sons?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21570721-upsurge-violence-streets-points-rising-instability-fathers-and-sons</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Czech presidency: Karel Havel or Milos Klaus?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130119_EUP002_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;372&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Schwarzenberg, on fire&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;TWO elder statesmen will now face each other in the race to succeed Vaclav Klaus, the famously Eurosceptic Czech president. Milos Zeman, a former prime minister, narrowly beat Karel Schwarzenberg, the current foreign minister, in the first round, with scores of 24.2% and 23.4%, respectively. A run-off will be held on January 25th and 26th.Mr Zeman had been expected to come first, but Mr Schwarzenberg more than doubled his predicted share. In doing so he edged out the second favourite, Jan Fischer, another former prime minister. Mr Fischer, who was bleeding support in the campaign’s final weeks, ended up in third place with 16.4% of the vote. The Social Democrats’ candidate, Jiri Dienstbier (son of a famous ex-dissident), was the only other to surpass 7%: he got 16.1%.Some 61.3% of Czech voters cast their ballots in what was their first direct election for president. This came after a constitutional change last year that did away with a convoluted parliamentary process rife with back-room dealing. Even an elected head of state will have limited powers, but he helps to shape public opinion as well as formally...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569758-choice-voters-next-czech-president-karel-havel-or-milos-klaus?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569758-choice-voters-next-czech-president-karel-havel-or-milos-klaus</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 January 2013 16:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France’s president: François Hollande’s new war trappings</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/01/articles/main/20130119_EUD001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;EVER since President François Hollande was elected last May, things have not gone right for him. He promised to kick-start growth and create jobs, yet the economy has stalled, factories keep closing and unemployment is over 10%. His scheme to impose a 75% top income-tax rate on millionaires has been ruled unconstitutional by the highest court. Up to 1m protesters have challenged his plans to legalise gay adoption and marriage. As his credibility has drooped, so have his poll numbers, to record lows. Yet in the past week, Mr Hollande has silenced even his critics by revealing an unexpected streak of audacity.First came the decision on January 11th to order French air strikes on an Islamist incursion from northern Mali into government-held territory. With no warning, Mr Hollande sent French fighter jets, based in France and nearby Chad, as well as attack helicopters, to strike a rebel column advancing towards Bamako, the capital. After days of air strikes, in which one French helicopter pilot was killed, Jean-Yves Le Drian, the French defence minister, said that the Islamist groups, which have ties to al-Qaeda, had been partially pushed back. By mid-week...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569751-new-more-decisive-french-president-may-have-emerged-many-old-troubles-still-lie?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569751-new-more-decisive-french-president-may-have-emerged-many-old-troubles-still-lie</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 January 2013 16:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lower Saxony: Germany’s Missouri</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GERMANY’S politicians are criss-crossing the icy state of Lower Saxony in a mad dash to win the vote there on January 20th, seen as a test run for this autumn’s federal election. But political boffins are interested for another reason. The state is not just a good representation of Germany, but has also become an incubator of political talent.  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130119_EUM935.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;263&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;Uwe Alschner, a political strategist, likens it to Missouri, which American wonks study because it is in parts southern, western and mid-western, and is both urban and rural. Lower Saxony is part Catholic (in the west) and part Protestant. It has lots of farms but is also industrial (the home of Volkswagen) and urban, with several clusters of innovation. It has regional dialects but also the German accent seen as the most neutral of all: Hanoverian.This gives Lower Saxony’s politicians an edge. The &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Weisswurstäquator&lt;/em&gt; (“white-sausage equator”), named after a Bavarian sausage and running east-west along the Main river, usually demarcates the cultural boundary south of which politicians are too exotic to get ahead in national politics. Among northern states, North Rhine-Westphalia, home to the largest...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569762-cross-section-country-and-bellwether-its-politics-germanys-missouri?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569762-cross-section-country-and-bellwether-its-politics-germanys-missouri</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 January 2013 16:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia’s government: Tottering on</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130119_EUP001_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Making suggestions in Ljubljana&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;THE government is “clinically dead”, declared &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Delo&lt;/em&gt;, a Slovenian daily, on January 15th. The question is how long it can last in this state. Some say Janez Jansa, the prime minister, will step down within days; others expect him to cling on. His office dismisses talk of resignation. Yet Tomaz Saunik, a political analyst, concludes that “one way or another, he will fall”.Since November Slovenia has sizzled with protests. On January 8th the official anti-corruption commission dropped a bombshell by saying that Mr Jansa and Zoran Jankovic, leader of the largest parliamentary party, which is in opposition, had questions to answer. Both men, said the commission, “systematically and repeatedly violated the law” by failing to report their assets. Mr Jansa, already on trial for corruption, should say how he came by more than €200,000 ($265,000) of “unknown origin”. Mr Jankovic, who is also mayor of Ljubljana, should explain relations between firms owned by his sons, companies doing business with the city and cash transferred to his private account. On January 11th, 10,000 protesters...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569754-government-and-opposition-are-both-their-last-legs-tottering?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569754-government-and-opposition-are-both-their-last-legs-tottering</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 January 2013 16:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain’s government: Rosy scenario</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN MADRID ministers brag that they have turned a corner. Euro-zone bond yields have been hitting new low levels (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/news/finance-and-economics/21569727-government-bond-markets-peripheral-countries-are-soaring-time-celebrate&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;). Spain’s banking and labour reforms are now in place. Growth will revive later this year or in 2014. Jobs, the Spanish El Dorado, will eventually follow.But that is surely too rosy a view. Exports are growing and the current account is now in surplus, but even the government sees GDP shrinking by 0.5% in 2013 (and most analysts talk of 1.5%). Spaniards are suffering an aching spell of record unemployment, at 26.6%. Austerity means worsening public services just as real wage and pension cuts make people poorer. The biggest asset for many families, their house, is plunging in value, with a further 20% price fall expected. Higher income, sales and housing taxes will hit spending power further. Business confidence and retail sales are in retreat. And a housing glut will take years to digest. Only 25,655 of what Fitch, a ratings agency, says are 1.2m unsold Spanish houses were bought in November.Spain must eventually emerge from all this. But will Spaniards put up with extended pain? Or will they rebel against a political establishment that has failed them? So far they have been...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569755-spanish-government-newly-optimistic-many-spaniards-are-not-rosy-scenario?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569755-spanish-government-newly-optimistic-many-spaniards-are-not-rosy-scenario</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 January 2013 16:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia: To privatise or not to privatise</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN THE 1990s privatisation in Russia was meant to be a way to wipe clean the vestiges of the Soviet economy and to create a new class of property owners. It had some success but, by creating a class of very rich oligarchs, it both weakened the state and planted seeds of resentment among ordinary Russians. Yet when he was inaugurated as president again last May, Vladimir Putin signed a decree calling for the sale of all state holdings in firms outside the defence and energy industries by 2016.The aims may be different from the 1990s: to import foreign know-how, to attract investors and to improve corporate governance, as well as filling state coffers. But a political angle matters too. It goes back to the presidency of Dmitry Medvedev (now Mr Putin’s prime minister), who three years ago announced plans to sell off up to $100 billion of state assets. Talking up privatisation, says Alexander Kliment of Eurasia Group, a consultancy, was part of the “game of using Medvedev as a foil for the more statist Putin.” Now that the Medvedev interregnum is over, the mood has shifted back to a state-capitalist model.October’s huge $55 billion deal under which the state-owned oil giant Rosneft is buying 100% of TNK-BP does not explicitly affect plans for privatisation. Some officials even tried to portray it as part of them, since BP will end up with a 20% stake in Rosneft. The economy...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569756-russian-government-has-ambitious-plans-privatisationsupposedly-privatise-or-not?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569756-russian-government-has-ambitious-plans-privatisationsupposedly-privatise-or-not</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 January 2013 16:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlemagne: Europe in a foreign field</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130119_EUD000_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;WHEN young men go to war resentment turns against those shirking danger. In Iraq the Americans denounced the French as cheese-eating surrender monkeys. In the intervention in Mali, French politicians are dismayed by the absence of allies, especially Europeans, in the fight against jihadists.The French conservative opposition leader, Jean-François Copé, was among those complaining that “for now, our country is alone at the front.” Plantu, cartoonist for &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Le Monde&lt;/em&gt;, had President François Hollande as Tintin riding into battle, with the European Union depicted as the comically inept policemen, Dupond et Dupont (Thomson and Thompson in the English version), calling from their couch: “We are all with you!”Such criticism is harsh. The British, the Belgians, Danes, Italians, Germans and Canadians offered airlift support; the Americans are thinking of offering intelligence and air-to-air refuelling. French officials, who usually deride Cathy Ashton, the EU’s foreign-policy chief, are pleased she called an emergency meeting of foreign ministers on January 17th, and is ready to speed the deployment of a planned military training mission to Mali....&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569718-europeans-ability-deploy-force-abroad-falling-mali-shows-it-still-needed-europe?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569718-europeans-ability-deploy-force-abroad-falling-mali-shows-it-still-needed-europe</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 January 2013 16:04:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italian politics: Allies again</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130112_EUP003_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Mr Maroni’s Faustian pact&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;THE Northern League has long been decisive in Silvio Berlusconi’s political career. When in 1994 the party withdrew its support from his first government, he lost power. It was not until after the League’s founder, Umberto Bossi, teamed up with Mr Berlusconi again in 2000 that he was able to regain it.So the media proprietor-turned-conservative politician was understandably jubilant when he revealed on January 7th that he had wooed the League’s leaders back into an alliance they deserted after the fall of his latest government in November 2011. Recent opinion polls have given the League, which wants greater autonomy for the north and tighter immigration controls, less than 6% of the national vote. Yet it remains crucial to the prospects of the Italian right in the general election scheduled for February 24th and 25th.The electoral rules, framed eight years ago by a minister from the League, tip the scales in the race for the Senate towards parties with a geographically concentrated following. The centre-left Democratic Party (PD) is currently well ahead in the polls. But a partnership between the League...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569451-silvio-berlusconi-resuscitates-his-partys-alliance-northern-league-allies-again?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569451-silvio-berlusconi-resuscitates-his-partys-alliance-northern-league-allies-again</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 January 2013 16:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hungarian politics: A blow for Viktor Orban</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE new year has not started well for Viktor Orban, Hungary’s populist prime minister. On January 4th the Constitutional Court threw out his plan to redesign the electoral system.The court ruled that a new electoral law requiring voters to pre-register before the next general election (likely to take place in the spring of 2014) was unconstitutional. The law required voters to register online, a cumbersome and bureaucratic process, or in person, at least two weeks beforehand. The court said that only voter registration for ethnic Hungarians outside the borders, some 370,000 of whom have applied for citizenship, was legal. The court also struck down restrictions on campaign advertising in the run-up to the vote.Critics said the law discriminated against the poor, many of whom do not have access to the internet, are suspicious of officialdom, and are more likely to vote for the opposition. The government denied this and said the law was needed to update the electoral register. Yet it swiftly conceded defeat.The court’s decision is a big blow to Mr Orban and his Fidesz party. Last-minute voters tend to vote for opposition parties and support for Fidesz is slipping. A survey last month by Ipsos gave the Socialists 16%, compared to 19% for Fidesz. Support for Jobbik, the far-right party, slid to 6%.Fidesz had planned to use electoral registration to focus on its core supporters...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569456-support-prime-minister-seems-be-fading-fast-blow-viktor-orban?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569456-support-prime-minister-seems-be-fading-fast-blow-viktor-orban</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 January 2013 16:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French political language: Lost in translation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130112_EUD001_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;391&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;/div&gt;A TIMELY gift landed unexpectedly on &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;The Economist’s &lt;/em&gt;desk during the holidays. Entitled “Lost in Translation: a glossary of new French doublespeak”, it offers a handy guide to decoding political speech under François Hollande’s Socialist government. Both the left and the right in France have a tradition of disguising policy with woolly or euphemistic turns of phrase. Lionel Jospin, a Socialist prime minister, for instance, privatised more companies than his right-wing predecessors without ever using the word, preferring “opening up the capital”. For those bemused by the linguistic ambiguity of Mr Hollande’s team, here are some helpful extracts from the glossary:&lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Sécurisation de l’emploi&lt;/em&gt; (improving job security): phrase used to launch current labour-market negotiations, designed to introduce more flexibility (see banned words).&lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Partenaires sociaux&lt;/em&gt; (social partners): unions and bosses who do such negotiating, not to be confused with dating, square-dancing, doubles tennis etc.&lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Flexibilité &lt;/em&gt;(flexibility): outlawed word prompting grim visions of unregulated Anglo-Saxon...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569430-glossary-new-french-doublespeak-lost-translation?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569430-glossary-new-french-doublespeak-lost-translation</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 January 2013 16:11:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkey and the PKK: Peace at last?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MIGHT 2013 herald lasting peace between Turkey and its restive Kurds? The question has consumed the country ever since Recep Tayyip Erdogan, Turkey’s prime minister, confirmed that his national spy chief, Hakan Fidan, had been holding talks with Abdullah Ocalan, the Kurdish leader, on the prison island off Istanbul where he has been held in solitary confinement ever since his capture in 1999.Soon afterwards a pair of pro-Kurdish deputies were also granted their long-running wish to meet Mr Ocalan. The goal, Mr Erdogan declared, was to persuade the PKK to disarm; but under exactly what conditions continues to be a matter of frenzied speculation.Mr Erdogan is clearly staking his political future on fixing Turkey’s stickiest problem. The move to go public about the talks has confounded his fans and critics alike. Mr Erdogan has spent much of the past year horrifying liberal supporters with threats to revive the death penalty, raining insults on the “corpse loving” BDP (a pro-Kurdish party), vowing to crush the rebels through military might, and imprisoning hundreds of Kurdish politicians and activists on the thinnest of charges. Mr Erdogan’s hawkish outbursts coincided with the collapse in 2011 of an earlier round of negotiations, with each side blaming the other for their demise. Either way, the accepted wisdom was that Mr Erdogan, who is serving a third and (under internal...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569436-turkish-government-holding-talks-kurdish-leader-peace-last?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569436-turkish-government-holding-talks-kurdish-leader-peace-last</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 January 2013 16:11:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlemagne: Celtic metamorphosis</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130112_EUD000_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;“CAN’T wait to celebrate” declare posters at Dublin airport with a picture of revellers enjoying fireworks. The marketing of “The Gathering”, a year-long succession of festivals and feel-good events, is meant to draw the Irish diaspora back to the ancestral island. Some scornfully see this as a mere ploy to squeeze dollars from sentimental foreigners. A stronger criticism is that the Irish clans are scattering once more. Emigration, Ireland’s traditional response to its economic woes, has resumed and is even accelerating.Ballads have long evoked the sorrow of separation. “Many young men of twenty said goodbye,” sang The Dubliners in the 1960s. By the 1980s the archetypal emigrant was not just the poor labourer but the frustrated graduate. Then the economic boom of the “Celtic Tiger” years seemed to break the curse. Young men and women could get well-paid jobs at home. Ireland attracted back some of the departed, whose skills and networks acquired abroad fuelled the boom. For the first time Ireland drew in many foreign workers, especially from eastern Europe.That the Irish are once again on the move is taken as one more indictment of the incompetent political...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569437-ireland-model-adjustment-through-austerity-celtic-metamorphosis?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569437-ireland-model-adjustment-through-austerity-celtic-metamorphosis</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 January 2013 16:11:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany’s Free Democrats: The endangered queenmaker</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130112_EUP001_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;THE most successful political group in the Federal Republic of Germany has arguably been the Free Democratic Party (FDP). Since 1949, it has been in government—always as junior partner—more than either of the two main parties, the centre-right Christian Democratic Union (CDU) and the centre-left Social Democrats (SPD). The FDP’s classical-liberal values of individual freedom, limited government and rule of law inspired Germany’s post-war constitution. The party also fielded two respected presidents, Theodor Heuss and Walter Scheel, as well as Germany’s most influential foreign minister, Hans-Dietrich Genscher. In 2009, in the most recent federal election, the party got its best result ever, with 14.6% of votes.  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130112_EUC736.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;How it has fallen. The party is now so low in the polls that it risks dropping below the 5% threshold required to enter the state parliament in Lower Saxony, which votes on January 20th, and even the Bundestag in September’s federal...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569399-angela-merkels-hold-power-may-yet-depend-fate-germanys-struggling-liberal-party?fsrc=rss|eur</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21569399-angela-merkels-hold-power-may-yet-depend-fate-germanys-struggling-liberal-party</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 January 2013 16:11:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>