<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Economist: United States</title>
    <description>United States</description>
    <link>http://www.economist.com</link>
    <image>
      <link>http://www.economist.com</link>
      <width>125</width>
      <title>Economist.com</title>
      <url>//media.economist.com/sites/all/themes/econfinal/images/the-economist-logo.gif</url>
      <height>34</height>
    </image>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <webMaster>webmaster@economist.com</webMaster>
    <managingEditor>rondiorio@economist.com</managingEditor>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <docs>http://www.economist.com/rss/</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The economy: Deficit-reduction disorder</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130209_USP001_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;WITH the financial crisis over and the recovery gaining momentum, one big piece of unfinished economic business hangs over Barack Obama’s second term: arresting the relentless rise in America’s already sky-high debt. He is turning to the task with what seems an improbable claim: that the job is closer to completion than people appreciate.There is, however, some truth to it. On February 5th the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) forecast that for the fiscal year ending on September 30th the deficit will clock in at $845 billion, or 5.3% of GDP, the lowest figure since 2008 and down by nearly half from its peak of 10.1% in 2009, Mr Obama’s first year in office.To be sure, that projection assumes that Mr Obama and Congress do not override planned spending cuts and tax rises, most importantly the “sequester”. The sequester mandates $1.1 trillion of additional spending cuts over the next ten years, including $85 billion-worth this year that are due to begin on March 1st after being put off for two months. Even if those measures are overridden, the CBO still predicts that the deficit will fall to 5.5% this year and 3.7% of GDP by 2015. Thereafter, though, it will...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571456-austerity-and-economic-recovery-are-bringing-down-deficit-long-term-problem?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571456-austerity-and-economic-recovery-are-bringing-down-deficit-long-term-problem</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murder rates: Feeling the heat</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130209_USP004_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Chicago Scene Investigation&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;“IT IS easier to buy a gun or drugs here than food,” says Marcenia Richards, the executive director of the Peace Coalition Against Violence. Her group, part of the church of Saint Sabina, is trying to halt the tide of murder that is ravaging what is left of the community of Englewood, a rundown district of Chicago. Outside her church is a wall with the names of almost 100 children and young adults. A sign says: “We are not forgotten.”Killings like these are now less likely to be ignored, in large part because of the revulsion caused by the killing of 20 children at a Connecticut school in December. The death of a Chicago teenager, Hadiya Pendleton, who had recently performed in Barack Obama’s inauguration parade, got much attention. So did the agony of Shirley Chambers, who lost the last of her four children to gun violence in January.In tune with the national mood, the local mayor, Rahm Emanuel, well-known for his anti-gun views before his arrival in 2011, has become much more outspoken. He has begun to sever the city’s ties with companies that manufacture or sell assault weapons, and he is urging...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571477-gun-control-getting-increasingly-political-windy-city-feeling-heat?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571477-gun-control-getting-increasingly-political-windy-city-feeling-heat</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hillary Clinton bows out: A legacy at Foggy Bottom</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ON FEBRUARY 4th John Kerry put in his first full day as America’s top diplomat. He has busy boots to fill. During her four-year tenure Hillary Clinton, voted “most admired woman” by Americans for 11 years in a row, visited more countries (112) than any other secretary of state, held 1,700 meetings with world leaders and notched up almost a million miles in travel. She also, rather less conspicuously, oversaw a shake-up of the State Department.For the first time Foggy Bottom now houses its own chief economist, in line with Mrs Clinton’s vision of “economic statecraft”, one of her catchphrases, as well as a new Bureau of Energy Resources. Since January 2012 the department has also had an under-secretary of state for civilian security, democracy, and human rights, who heads what is known as the “J family”—a group of bureaus tied together by another favourite Clinton concept, the “three Ds” of national security: diplomacy, development and defence.These changes came as a result of the Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review (QDDR), the first of which was published in December 2010. Mrs Clinton got the inspiration for the report, which is modelled on the Pentagon’s Quadrennial Defence Review, during her time serving on the Senate Armed Services Committee. There, according to one official, she saw the benefit of “stepping back and not getting stuck in the immediate”, as the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571478-few-improvements-state-department-legacy-foggy-bottom?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571478-few-improvements-state-department-legacy-foggy-bottom</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The sequester and defence: Thinking the unthinkable</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/2013/02/articles/main/20130209_USD001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;296&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;THE automatic cuts imposed by Congress’s “sequester” on America’s budget fall heavily on defence, which accounts for at least half of discretionary spending. Faced with 9% across-the-board reductions, Leon Panetta, the outgoing secretary of defence, stalled for time. Thanks to the “fiscal cliff” deal done on January 1st, the administration bought the Pentagon a couple of months for his successor to prepare for the worst. But little else has changed. Add to this the similarly sized cuts in the defence budget already agreed on in 2011, and Pentagon planners who two years ago thought they would have $600 billion to spend this year will now have to make do with about $486 billion. Service chiefs are already wailing about a “readiness crisis” and a “hollowing out” of the force.The reality is even worse than the figures suggest. Military personnel costs, which absorb 34% of the Pentagon’s spending, count against the overall budget cap but are exempt from the cuts. Overseas operations are not exempt, but will be given priority. All other programmes and commitments will therefore have to be cut by around 15%, with little discretion over how and where the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571454-hopes-reprieve-pentagon-55-billion-year-cuts-are-fading-thinking?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571454-hopes-reprieve-pentagon-55-billion-year-cuts-are-fading-thinking</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential voting: Moving the goalposts</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN NEARLY every political race in a democracy, the rules are simple: the candidate who gets the most votes wins. The American presidency is a notable exception: four times in the past 200 years the loser of the popular vote has taken the oath of office. For three of those four cases, blame the Electoral College.  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130209_USM111.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;This unloved and Byzantine body emerged during America’s founding as a compromise between those who wished for direct popular election of a president and those who preferred the president to be elected by Congress. Hundreds of constitutional amendments have been floated to end or amend the Electoral College; yet it remains.Although the constitution mandates the existence of the Electoral College, states are free to decide how to apportion their electoral votes. In every state but two, the winner of the statewide popular vote gets all of the state’s electoral votes. The two exceptions, Nebraska and Maine, each give two electoral votes to the popular-vote winner, and apportion the rest to the popular-vote winner in each congressional district. That can produce splits. In 2008 John McCain won four of Nebraska’s five electoral votes by winning the popular...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571485-plan-change-electoral-college-carries-whiff-desperation-moving-goalposts?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571485-plan-change-electoral-college-carries-whiff-desperation-moving-goalposts</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ed Koch, 1924-2013: Farewell to the cheerleader</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/2013/02/articles/main/20130209_usp003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;395&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Top of the heap, king of the hill&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;“WHENEVER I would fly home, especially if it was at night, there was the city of New York laid out before me and I thought to myself, ‘This belongs to me. It’s extraordinary. Thank you God’,” said Ed Koch, the former mayor of New York, at the start of Neil Barsky’s documentary about him. By the time he died on February 1st, on the day the documentary came out, Mr Koch was as much a New York icon as that skyline he looked out on. Indeed, he was more popular in 2013 than when he left City Hall in 1989.He and the Big Apple were a good fit. When he took office, in 1978, the city was on its knees. A serial killer was targeting New Yorkers, crime was rampant, graffiti were pervasive, the Bronx was burning and the city was all but broke. As Michael Bloomberg, New York’s current mayor, put it, “When we were down, Ed Koch picked us up.” His catchphrase “How’m I doing?” charmed New Yorkers. He did so well at restoring their spirits and stabilising the city’s credit that his second election was more of a coronation. In his second term he launched a $5 billion affordable-housing programme, one of his...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571486-mayor-who-picked-up-americas-greatest-city-farewell-cheerleader?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571486-mayor-who-picked-up-americas-greatest-city-farewell-cheerleader</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The census: Some other race</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE noisy debate over how to fix America’s immigration system is mainly about the large and rapidly growing Hispanic minority. Behind this hums a quieter debate over how they should be counted. Every ten years the American government conducts a census of its citizens. Hispanics present a particular challenge.According to guidelines laid down by the federal Office of Management and Budget in 1977, “Hispanic” is an ethnicity, not a race. Someone of Hispanic origin may belong to any of the five officially recognised races: white, black, Asian, American Indian or Pacific Islander (or any combination of these). The census form reflects this distinction.  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130209_USP002_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;It’s complicated&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;This, however, is not how many American Hispanics have come to see themselves. In 2010, the last time a count was carried out, many were puzzled by a form that asked them first to declare whether or not they were of Hispanic origin, and then to say what race they belonged to. Half identified themselves as white. But over a third ticked a box marked “Some other race”. As a result, “some other” emerged as America’s third-largest racial grouping.This frustrates the head-...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571487-how-should-america-count-its-hispanics-some-other-race?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571487-how-should-america-count-its-hispanics-some-other-race</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lexington: Death in Little Rock</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130209_USD000_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;THANKS to a botched suicide bid that blew away part of his brain, the Arkansas murderer Ricky Ray Rector had no inkling of the link between his execution and the presidential ambitions of his state’s governor, Bill Clinton. Indeed, as he was taken to die by lethal injection (it took 50 minutes of jabbing to find a suitable vein), Rector saved the pecan pie from his last meal “for later”. It did not matter. Mr Clinton, who flew home to Arkansas from the 1992 campaign trail to oversee Rector’s death, had proved he was as tough on crime as any Republican.It was thus quite a moment when the present governor of Arkansas, Mike Beebe, said on January 16th that he would sign a bill repealing the death penalty if legislators sent him one. Deciding which prisoners deserved death had proved “agonising” and had changed his view of capital punishment, he explained. His reversal is largely symbolic: Mr Beebe, a conservative Democrat in a deeply conservative state, is not about to be sent an abolition bill. Nor is he seeking re-election. Yet his conversion is more than a curiosity. A growing band of governors is defying public sentiment on capital punishment, even though...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571428-politicians-national-ambitions-are-suddenly-willing-challenge-death?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571428-politicians-national-ambitions-are-suddenly-willing-challenge-death</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 February 2013 16:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lexington: Reporting for one last duty</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130202_USD000_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;BARACK OBAMA’s new secretary of state began his political career with a call for America to end a foreign entanglement. “How do you ask a man to be the last man to die for a mistake?” naval Lieutenant John Kerry asked a 1971 Senate hearing on the war in Vietnam. His question—given weight by his medal ribbons, officer’s fatigues and fellow-veterans massed outside—captured divisions tormenting his country, and brought instant fame.Two generations on and after 28 years as a member of that same Senate, Mr Kerry has landed the job of America’s chief diplomat; he was confirmed by his peers on January 29th by 94 votes to three. Success in the job will involve a reversal, and turn on persuading today’s war-weary Americans—starting with Mr Obama—to engage with the world and resist the urge to withdraw from foreign entanglements of all sorts.Though Mr Obama took his time deciding to give the post to Mr Kerry, supporters have high hopes. They point to the new secretary’s experience and networks of contacts, forged as a member of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, and latterly as a troubleshooting envoy for Mr Obama in such hotspots as Afghanistan, Pakistan and...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571133-derided-foes-flip-flopping-grandee-new-secretary-state-may-yet-do-vital?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571133-derided-foes-flip-flopping-grandee-new-secretary-state-may-yet-do-vital</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recess appointments: Obama oversteps</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JUST over a year ago, while most of his colleagues were home for the holidays, a lone senator entered the Capitol and banged the gavel twice. With the first knock he called the empty Senate to order; with the second he quickly adjourned it. Though no work was done, the exercise was repeated every few days.This is what the dull work of obstruction looks like. By forcing the Senate to call “pro forma” sessions, Republicans hoped to prevent Barack Obama from appointing a handful of contentious candidates to important posts. All high-level nominees must be approved by the Senate, unless the body has recessed, in which case a “recess appointment” can be made that lasts up to two years.Senator Obama watched the Democrats block George W. Bush’s nominees in just this way. But President Obama rather liked being able to appoint who he chose when he chose. So last January he decided that despite the gavel-banging the Senate had in fact recessed, and he was therefore free to appoint three members to the National Labour Relations Board (NLRB) and a director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), both controversial components of the president’s regulatory regime.At the time Republicans called it a cynical power grab, and on January 25th a three-judge panel of a federal appeals court agreed. If the president can decide when the Senate was in recess, then he can make...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571166-president-rebuked-exceeding-his-authority-obama-oversteps?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571166-president-rebuked-exceeding-his-authority-obama-oversteps</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand Central: The survivor</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130202_USP003_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;“EUROPE has its cathedrals and we have Grand Central Station,” said Philip Johnson, an architect, when he along with Jackie Kennedy Onassis and Kent Barwick, then a director of New York’s Municipal Art Society (MAS), fought to save the station from demolition in the 1970s. It took a Supreme Court decision to save the magnificent Beaux-Arts building; but it survived and launched its year-long centennial celebration on February 1st.The station’s architectural oddities, still delight. A concave ceiling in the main concourse depicting the constellations draws the eye upwards. The station helped create New York’s premiere business district, where 250,000 people work, and it still serves it well.The station’s construction was a vast undertaking: 25 miles of water and sewer lines had to be relocated, and 3m cubic yards of dirt and rock were excavated. Tracks were lowered underground and electrified and the ground above became Park Avenue. The station, since 1991 home to a commuter line and several subway lines, was once the main gateway to the rest of the country. In 1913, 75,000 passed through the station per day; today that number is 750,000, with 1m people...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571169-station-celebrates-its-centennial-new-york-looks-next-100-years?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571169-station-celebrates-its-centennial-new-york-looks-next-100-years</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juvenile justice: Suffer the children</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ON MARCH 29th 2012 Georgia’s Republican-controlled House of Representatives voted on a criminal-justice reform bill that read like a left-leaning criminologist’s fantasy. It revised sentencing laws to keep non-violent drug and property offenders out of prison, directing them instead toward alternatives—drug courts, day-reporting centres, mental-health courts—designed to treat and rehabilitate rather than punish. It invested millions of dollars in such programmes—not an easy sell in times of tight budgets. And it created graduated scales of punishment, allowing the law to distinguish between someone with a single joint and someone with a pound of marijuana. The House passed the bill unanimously. The Republican-controlled state Senate did the same, and Nathan Deal, Georgia’s Republican governor, signed it into law.Now Georgia is looking to do something similar for juveniles. The impetus is the same: high costs and poor return on investment. Nearly two-thirds of Georgia’s juvenile-justice department’s annual $300m budget goes to running residential facilities, which cost $91,126 per bed per year for long-term facilities and $88,155 for short-term. By way of comparison, the annual fee for students at Riverside Military Academy, a private boarding school just north of Atlanta, is $29,750.But while most graduates of Riverside go on to better things, graduates of Georgia’s...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571176-georgia-rethinks-how-its-justice-system-deals-young-offenders-suffer-children?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571176-georgia-rethinks-how-its-justice-system-deals-young-offenders-suffer-children</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigration reform: Washington learns a new language</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130202_USP001_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;THE growing power of immigrants in American politics was not just seen this week, but heard. As a cross-party group of senators unveiled an immigration reform plan on January 28th, including a pathway to citizenship for millions of illegal residents, two of their number turned to the cameras and delivered long statements in Spanish. One was a liberal Democrat, Robert Menendez of New Jersey. The second was Marco Rubio of Florida, a tea-party hero and likely contender for the Republican presidential nomination in 2016.While conceding that it would be unfair if lawbreakers secured papers ahead of migrants who had obeyed the rules—a key complaint of conservatives opposed to previous amnesty plans—Mr Rubio spoke warmly of his own immigrant family. He pointed to the 11m migrants in America without papers, an overwhelming majority of whom had come seeking a better life, just like “our parents and grandparents”. America, he said, needed laws that were responsible but “humane”.Mr Rubio’s plea for compassion contrasted with the 2012 Republican presidential primary, during which candidates vied to denounce immigration plans that smacked of amnesty. Jump back to the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571178-leap-forward-towards-more-sensible-system-many-more-steps-will-be?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571178-leap-forward-towards-more-sensible-system-many-more-steps-will-be</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The economy: The little dipper</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT IS is hardly news that America’s economic recovery has been sluggish. After all, last year’s presidential election was waged largely over the issue. Yet it still came as a shock to most forecasters, let alone the public, when the government reported on January 30th that the economy actually shrank in the fourth quarter, for the first time since the recession ended in mid-2009.The decline in gross domestic product, at 0.1%, was slight, and could easily be revised away. The swing in growth from a healthy 3.1% in the third quarter was down to several components whose behaviour probably says little about the future. Private stock-building fell sharply, subtracting 1.3 percentage points from growth. Federal defence spending, which had surged in the third quarter, fell back sharply in the fourth, wiping out another 1.3 points.Defence spending is always lumpy (planes and destroyers are not purchased on a daily basis), but its behaviour recently has been especially strange. Ben Herzon of Macroeconomic Advisers, a consultancy, said the fluctuations were concentrated in contracts for installation, weapons and personnel support services, which rose by the largest on record in the third quarter and fell by the largest on record in the fourth. Finally, exports fell, a victim of the febrile state of the global economy.  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571181-luck-fourth-quarter-was-aberration-little-dipper?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571181-luck-fourth-quarter-was-aberration-little-dipper</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Lakes: The shipping news</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHEN spring arrives and the frozen shores of the Great Lakes are long thawed, the St Lawrence Seaway, North America’s liquid superhighway, should witness the greatest renewal of its shipping fleet in 30 years. Craig Middlebrook, the deputy administrator of the St Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation (which operates and maintains the American portion of seaway) reckons about 30 new ships are being built to ply its waters.One of the latest to be launched was the &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Federal Satsuki &lt;/em&gt;commissioned by the Fednav Group, based in Montreal. She set sail from Cleveland in December. Part of the reason for this fleet renewal is the removal of duty on Canadian flagships built abroad in places like China and Japan. Another is that currency fluctuations have made it cheaper to acquire new vessels.Yet as Rod Jones, the CEO of CSL Group, a shipping firm, says, “we have been waiting for a buying opportunity.” And the reason that many other companies feel the same way is that there is a widely held view that the Great Lakes region is poised for long-term economic growth. The shipping companies want to be ready for it.Mr Middlebrook says the rebirth of American heavy manufacturing, led by the automotive industry, has been a bright spot for shipping recently. Furthermore, in the long term, the development of shale gas and oil looks as though it will not only increase...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571186-despite-problems-revival-shipping-great-lakes-expected-shipping-news?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571186-despite-problems-revival-shipping-great-lakes-expected-shipping-news</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s maritime infrastructure: Crying out for dollars</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/01/articles/main/20130202_USP004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Who needs trucks?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;THE Industrial Canal Lock in New Orleans connects two of America’s highest-tonnage waterways: the Mississippi River—which handles more than 6,000 ocean vessels, 150,000 barges and 500m tonnes of cargo each year, as well as much of its grain, corn and soyabean production—and the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway, which runs from refinery-rich south-eastern Texas to Florida. Ships pass from one to the other via a lock that was built in 1921, and is 600 usable feet long, or half the length of a modern lock. Its replacement was authorised in 1956. Construction on the replacement was authorised in 1998, and then stalled by lawsuits. The most optimistic predictions of the Army Corps of Engineers, which maintains America’s inland waterways, see the new lock being completed in 2030.  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/2013/01/articles/body/20130202_USC829.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;A few miles upriver from this archaism sits the Port of New Orleans, one of America’s busiest and most diverse. Like its...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571167-underinvestment-ports-and-inland-waterways-imperils-american-competitiveness-crying-out?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21571167-underinvestment-ports-and-inland-waterways-imperils-american-competitiveness-crying-out</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 January 2013 16:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlantic City: Changing the game</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-full&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130126_USP006_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#039;caption&#039;&gt;Let the Revel now begin&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;THE SugarHouse Casino on the Delaware river in Philadelphia was packed on a recent federal holiday. The slot machines were almost all occupied. The betting tables were busy. The car park was nearly full. SugarHouse, along with Pennsylvania’s ten other casinos, has been siphoning away much of Atlantic City’s gambling business. So much so that Pennsylvania, which did not open a casino until 2006, is now the second-largest gambling market in America after Las Vegas, bypassing the “City by the Sea”, which held a monopoly on gambling in the north-east for nearly 30 years. Atlantic City has just ended its sixth straight year of falling revenues.The growth of gambling in neighbouring states, especially Pennsylvania and New York, Atlantic City’s main markets, has severely affected gaming revenues in the city itself. Pennsylvania’s lawmakers placed casinos in or near big population centres. Philadelphia, which is only 65 miles (105km) from Atlantic City, has four new casinos in or near it. Advertisements on New York’s subway remind commuters that gaming is now minutes away, not hours. In New Jersey casino gambling...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570757-innovative-thinking-needed-city-sea-changing-game?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570757-innovative-thinking-needed-city-sea-changing-game</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Criminal justice and the courts: Thumb on the scale</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AARON SWARTZ , who committed suicide two weeks ago, had been arrested for illegally downloading millions of articles from JSTOR, an archive of academic journals. Once Mr Swartz had returned the material and promised not to distribute or use it, JSTOR pressed no charges. That did not mollify federal prosecutors. They charged him with 13 felony counts, including wire fraud, computer fraud and criminal forfeiture. Then they offered him a deal familiar to criminal defendants everywhere: plead guilty, and get off relatively easily—in his case, six months in a “low security setting”—or take your chances at trial, and face a harsher sentence if you lose. For Mr Swartz, that could have meant a sentence of decades in prison and fines exceeding $1m.Plea bargains such as this have long been part of the American legal system. In theory they work to the benefit of all parties. The defendant admits his guilt and gets a lighter sentence; the prosecutor notches up a win; and the court is spared the time and cost of holding a trial. The reality is far murkier.Until the early 20th century, plea-bargaining was widely considered corrupt. But as the number of criminal statutes grew, so did the stress on the courts, and the consequent need to avoid endless trials. During Prohibition the number of criminal cases soared: by 1930 almost eight times as many people were prosecuted for violating the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570742-how-mandatory-minimum-sentences-distort-plea-bargaining-thumb-scale?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570742-how-mandatory-minimum-sentences-distort-plea-bargaining-thumb-scale</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidents and the economy: Second-term blues</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130126_USC804.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;417&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;Is there a curse of a second term?Anecdotally, presidents&#039; last years in&amp;nbsp;office seem to go pear-shaped where the&amp;nbsp;economy is concerned. The data bear this&amp;nbsp;out.We looked at all 11 presidents who served&amp;nbsp;two terms after Teddy Roosevelt took&amp;nbsp;office in September 1901 (including any&amp;nbsp;president who served across two&amp;nbsp;administrations, even if, like Calvin&amp;nbsp;Coolidge, Harry Truman, Lyndon Johnson&amp;nbsp;and Richard Nixon, he did not serve two&amp;nbsp;full terms). Most second administrations&amp;nbsp;had worse economic performances across&amp;nbsp;seven common indicators (measured by&amp;nbsp;comparing the average change between&amp;nbsp;the start and the end of each term). Only&amp;nbsp;three of the 11 re-elected presidents Bill&amp;nbsp;Clinton, Ronald Reagan and Truman&amp;nbsp;experienced better economies in their&amp;nbsp;second terms. Will Barack Obama turn out&amp;nbsp;to be the fourth?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570736-second-term-blues?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570736-second-term-blues</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The economy: Looking better</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;content-image-float&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130126_USC839.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;  width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;WHEN Barack Obama took office four years ago, the economic figures were terrifying. A financial crisis and a savage recession were in full swing, and house foreclosures were soaring. As he was sworn in, panic about the banks sent the Dow Jones Industrial Average down more than 300 points. At the start of his second term, by contrast, the Dow hit a five-year high, while a widely followed index of investor fear called the VIX reached a near-six-year low (see table).This change in mood is understandable. The financial crisis and recession ended more than three years ago. The housing market is firmly on the mend. Employment is growing. The euro zone, though feeble, is no longer about to collapse. And the threat of home-grown crisis appeared to recede when Republicans in the House forbore to use the threat of default to extract spending cuts. This week they voted to raise the Treasury’s statutory ceiling until May 18th; previously, the Treasury had expected to run out of borrowing authority as early as mid-February.On average, the economy performs less well in a president’s second term than in his first (for&amp;nbsp;full results see...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570738-some-risks-less-fear-second-term-gets-under-way-looking-better?fsrc=rss|ust</link>
      <guid isPermaLink = "false">http://www.economist.com/news/united-states/21570738-some-risks-less-fear-second-term-gets-under-way-looking-better</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 January 2013 16:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
